<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A proposal for supplying His Majesty with twelve hundred thousand pounds, by mending the coin, and yet preserve the ancient standard of the kingdom. / By a Gentleman.</title>
            <author>L. R., gentleman.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1695</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 52 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 13 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A92198</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing R41</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R233588</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">45097905</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 45097905</idno>
            <idno type="VID">171482</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A92198)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 171482)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2575:28)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A proposal for supplying His Majesty with twelve hundred thousand pounds, by mending the coin, and yet preserve the ancient standard of the kingdom. / By a Gentleman.</title>
                  <author>L. R., gentleman.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[4], 20 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed, and are to be sold by John Whitlock near Stationers-Hall,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London: :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1695.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Dedication signed: L.R.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Glasgow University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Finance, Public --  Great Britain --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Currency question --  Great Britain --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Economic policy --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-10</date>
            <label>Jason Colman</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-10</date>
            <label>Jason Colman</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:171482:1"/>
            <p>A PROPOSAL FOR Supplying His MAJESTY WITH Twelve hundred thouſand Pounds, By Mending the COIN, AND Yet Preſerve the Ancient Standard of the Kingdom.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>By a Gentleman.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON:</hi> Printed, and are to be Sold by <hi>John Whitlock</hi> near <hi>Stationers-Hall,</hi> 1695.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="letter">
            <pb facs="tcp:171482:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:171482:2"/>
            <head>To the Right Honourable the Lords Commiſſioners of His Majeſties Treaſury.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>May it pleaſe your Lordſhips,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>THE preſſing Neceſſities of His Majeſty for ſpeedy and effectual Supplies to carry on the preſent War with <hi>France,</hi> the badneſs of our Coin, and the Deſigns of ſome People, to bring a Diſ-reputation upon His Majeſty, by altering the Ancient Standard thereof, put me upon ſome thoughts, how all theſe Inconveniencies might in ſome meaſure be accommodated; which I think (with Submiſſion to your Lordſhips better Judgments) may by the following Method eaſily be obtained. But after I had (by the ſmall Intervals of times the preſſure of my own Affairs gave me) accompliſhed the ſame, I came to a ſight of the Book written by that Moſt Ingenious Gentleman Mr. <hi>Lowndes,</hi> which I could have wiſh'd had been ſooner, that (according to my weak Capacity) I might have particularly anſwered his Reaſons for Lightning the Standard of our Money, to the Foot of Six ſhillings and five pence half-penny the Ounce, which that my preſſure of Buſineſs will not now give me leave to do; and therefore, as it is, beg your Lordſhips favourable Acceptance thereof, only crave leave to mind your Honours, of the ſtrenuous Arguments urged hy him againſt Debaſing our Standard by Allay, to which I think my ſelf happy to agree; but at the ſame time extreamly Wonder, he doth not perceive they bear the ſame Force and Energy againſt debaſing it by Weight; For it can admit of no Diſpute, that Debaſing our Standard Twenty five <hi>per Cent.</hi> by Allay, or debaſing it twenty five <hi>per Cent.</hi> by weight, (which is what he argues for) is both the ſame thing. But the miſtaken Ground of his reaſoning herein, ariſes from the preſent great Price of Bullion, whilst he conſiders not the Badneſs of our Money is the occaſion thereof; and that as if the Money be new coined at Six ſhillings and five pence half-penny the Ounce, Bullion will bear that price; ſo if it could be coined at the preſent Standard, it will bear but five ſhillings two pence the Ounce; unleſs, as it will in both Caſes, bear two pence or three pence an Ounce more when we are to pay our Debts abroad; and muſt pay it in Bullion, becauſe our Laws has prevented us paying it in Money, which would be quite the contrary, were that I have here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after propoſed permitted to be done: And therefore I may conclude, That upon ſecond thoughts he will joyn Iſſue with me, that our Standard of Allay and Weight are both the ſame thing, and ought, for the Honour of His Majeſty, and Juſtice to his People, inviolably to be preſerved, Eſpecially ſince it will cost the Nation, by his own Calculation (and therein he has the General Opinion) but five hundred thouſand Pounds more, than it will if debaſed to this Standard: A ſmall Pit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance in compariſon to what I have made out muſt be loſt by the Landlords thereby. Upon the whole, If the Money muſt be new Coined, the Standard ought to be kept Sacred; but whether it be or be not, when it is ſo new Coined, it
<pb facs="tcp:171482:3"/>may well be feared (whilſt the War last) we ſhall be attended with greater Evils than now, and that Conſumption we now linger under, be turned to im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mediate Death, by our Forreign Creditors taking from us what we owe them in Specie, or worſer, making us pay Exorbitant Interest for the ſame. And therefore ſince the greateſt Miſchiefs of our Coin, in bringing it into Diſ-repu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation with our common People at home, proceeds rather from the Counterfeits than Clipt Money, I have ſince thought, that (with Submiſſion to your Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhips) it might be better, during the War (unleſs, as in my Propoſals, for the Benefit of Supplying his Majeſty therewith) to ſcuffle on with our Clipt Money, than call it in: And that a Cure of our Counterfeits will be eaſily effected, if a Law were paſſed, that for the future all Receivers of the publick Revenues, and their Deputies or Clarks (if Perſons known to be well skill'd (as they ought to be) in the Goodneſs of Sterling Silver) and all Goldſmiths ſhall be obliged upon Oath, when any Money ſhall be tendered them in Payment, that beyond Diſpute appears to be made of Counterfeit Metal (upon Diſcovery thereof) to cut it in two, and return it to the Owners: And likewiſe if they offer any ſuch Counterfeits in Payment, and it be refuſed, they ſhall in the preſence of the ſaid Refuſer (if demanded) alſo cut it in two; which Practice will ſoon deſtroy that many headed Hydra, whilſt now People with Impunity offer Counterfeit Money to ſuch Receivers and Goldſmiths, and they again to the Subject, which makes a Vent for it, and cauſes a Vexation in Trade, by perpetual Circulation thereof. And though it is true, that ſuch Art will at firſt occaſion great Loſs to the Poſſeſſors thereof, yet ſince it is but what muſt fall upon them, if the Money be called in, they cannot ſurely Repine thereat. If any of my Thoughts herein, or in my following Propoſal, may ſtir up more able Heads to better Conceptions, or tend to the Service of His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty, and Good of my Fellow-Subjects, but eſpecially to the keeping up the Glory and Honour of our Sovereign, to the Standard of the Most Famous of his Predeceſſors, I have the End of my Ambition, deſiring no other Reward of my Labour; and therefore make uſe of this Method of Conveyance by the Penny-Poſt to your Lordſhips; and to be veiled under a Feigned Name, though otherwiſe,</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>London, <date>Nov. <hi>29. 1695.</hi>
                  </date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>
                  <hi>My Lords, Your Lordſhips moſt Humble, and moſt Obedient Servant</hi> L. R.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:171482:3"/>
            <head>
               <hi>A PROPOSAL FOR</hi> Supplying His Majeſty with Twelve Hundred Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Pounds <hi>Sterling,</hi> or more, for this Years Service of the War, Increaſing the Money (or at leaſt that which is as good as the Money) of the Nation to the like Sum of Twelve Hundred Thouſand Pounds; and making a great ſtep to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards Altering the Coin, by calling in the moſt <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ncurrant part thereof; that is, the Crowns and Half Crows <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nmill'd, which indeed are now almoſt become uſeleſs Caſh; and yet nevertheleſs ſtill to preſerve the Ancient Standard of the Kingdom. Together with ſome of the Advantages of this Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſal Demonſtrated, and Objections thereto Anſwered.</head>
            <p n="1">1. <hi>FIRST,</hi> Allowing that (according to the General Opi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nion) the Caſh of the Nation may be Six Millions of Pounds, it may be very well ſuppoſed, that one Third of it is Crowns and Half Crowns; which being new Coin'd, will at leaſt produce Twelve Hundred Thouſand Pounds, accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the Standard of <hi>England.</hi> It is therefore Propoſed, That all unmill'd Crowns and Half Crowns ſhall by Act of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment be made unlawful to utter in Payment after the Twenty Ninth Day of <hi>September,</hi> 1696.</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="tcp:171482:4"/>
            <p n="2">2. <hi>Secondly,</hi> That by the Twenty Fifth Day of <hi>March,</hi> 1696. a ſufficient Number of Skilful Perſons be appointed by His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty as Commiſſioners, to take in all Crowns and Half Crowns unmill'd, bearing the Stamp of <hi>Engliſh</hi> Money, which according to the beſt of their Skill they believe to be made of <hi>Sterling</hi> Sil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver; that being the only Rule now left to know which is the Coin of the Kingdom, by reaſon it is now ſo defaced by Clip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ping; and in that, their Judgment rather to incline to the Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour of the Subject.</p>
            <p n="3">3. <hi>Thirdly,</hi> That immediately upon delivering in ſuch Crowns and Half Crowns to ſuch Commiſſioners, the Perſon bringing them to have a Bill or Bills, which ſhall be payable out of a Fund to be ſettled by Act of Parliament, with Intereſt at Three Pounds Sixteen Shillings and a Half Penny <hi>per Cent. per Annum,</hi> till payment of the Principal; and till ſuch payment, the Bills to be made Currant in all Payments as the Coin of the Kingdom, and the Poſſeſſor only entituled to them.</p>
            <p n="4">4. <hi>Fourthly,</hi> That notwithſtanding it ſhall be unlawful for any Perſon to utter in Payment any unmill'd Crowns and Half Crowns, after the Twenty Ninth Day of <hi>September,</hi> 1696. Yet it ſhall be Lawful for the ſaid Commiſſioners to take in any of them that they ſhall find to bear the Stamp of <hi>Engliſh</hi> Money, and which according to the beſt of their Skill they believe to be made of <hi>Sterling</hi> Silver, at any time before or until the Twenty Fifth Day of <hi>December,</hi> 1696. and not after; and the Proprie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor of ſuch Crowns or Half Crowns, then to have ſuch Bill or Bills given them as above, upon Condition, the Sum of Two Millions be not brought in by the ſaid Twenty Ninth Day of <hi>September,</hi> 1696. or before the Twenty Fifth Day of <hi>December,</hi> 1696.</p>
            <p n="5">5. <hi>Fifthly,</hi> That if after the ſaid Twenty Fifth Day of <hi>Decem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber,</hi> 1696. the ſaid Commiſſioners ſhall find, upon caſting up their Accompts, that there has not been delivered in to them in Crowns and Half Crowns, the Sum of Two Millions of Pounds, then it ſhall be Lawful for them to take in as much as ſhall be wanting to compleat the ſaid Sum in Clipp'd Shillings, of the Stamp of the Kingdom, which according to the beſt of their Skill they believe to be made of <hi>Sterling</hi> Silver, at any time on or before the Twenty Fifth Day of <hi>March,</hi> 1697. And the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prietors of ſuch Shillings to have a Bill or Bills given them, as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove.</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:171482:4"/>
            <p n="6">6. <hi>Sixthly,</hi> That if on or before the Twenty Ninth Day of <hi>September,</hi> 1696. there ſhall be brought in and tendred to the ſaid Commiſſioners in Crowns and Half Crowns, more than the ſaid Sum of Two Millions of Pounds <hi>Sterling,</hi> there ſhall be Cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tificates given under the Hands of at leaſt three of the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, to the Proprietors thereof, ſpecifying that they had in their poſſeſſions, ſo many Pounds, or leſs, in unmill'd Crowns and Half Crowns; which Certificates the ſaid Commiſſioners ſhall Regiſter, and deliver in an Abſtract of them to the next Seſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions of Parliament, in Order to the Relief of ſuch perſons.</p>
            <p n="7">7. <hi>Seventhly,</hi> That each reſpective Commiſſioner ſhall imme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diately upon Receipt of any ſuch Crowns and Half Crowns, or Shillings, deliver them into His Majeſty's Mint, in One Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Pounds in each parcel, taking a Receipt from the Comptro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ler, or his chief Clerk, mentioning the Weight of each One Hundred Pounds, and the ſame there to be new coined; One Third part into Half Crowns, One Third part more into Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, and the other Third part into Sixpences, according to the Standard of the Mint, and from thence, by the Comptroller, as faſt as coined, paid into His Majeſty's Exchequer; from whence, the ſame (the better to be diſperſed through the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom) ſhall be iſſued to the Treaſurer of the Navy, and all ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>propriated to the Service thereof for the Year 1696. but more eſpecially to the Seamens Wages; except (if the Parliament ſees convenient) Two Hundred Thouſand Pounds, which His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty may grant Leave to be Exported for payment of his Army in <hi>Flanders,</hi> that being near the Sum permitted by Act of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment to be Exported in the Year 1695. in <hi>Engliſh</hi> Bullion.</p>
            <p n="8">8. <hi>Eighthly,</hi> That if any Crowns or Half Crowns, within the ſaid time or times, ſhall be brought to any one of the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, which ſhall plainly appear to be made of Counter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feit Metal, each Commiſſioner (to prevent being tendred again to any of them) to have power to cut them in two, and deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver them (ſo cut) back to the Owners; and if any Diſpute ſhall ariſe, or it ſhall ſeem doubtful whether they be of <hi>Sterling</hi> Silver, or not, the perſon bringing them to apply themſelves to a Committee of the ſaid Commiſſioners, who ſhall appoint a place where to ſit <hi>de die in diem,</hi> to determine ſuch Differences; where three of them ſhall be ſufficient, and the majority of them agree<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, ſhall be Concluſive; and if thereupon it appears, they are
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:171482:5"/>made of Counterfeit Metal, the ſaid Commiſſioners to have power to cut them in two, and return them to the Owners, and if otherwiſe, to paſs them as good.</p>
            <div type="proposal">
               <head>To put this in Practice, it is Propoſed,</head>
               <p>Firſt, That a Tax be Granted to His Majeſty, and ſettled for ever, as a Fund, to pay half yearly, the Intereſt of Two Mil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lions of Pounds, at the Rate of Three Pounds Sixteen Shillings and a Half-penny <hi>per Cent. per Annum,</hi> amounting to Seventy Six Thouſand Forty One Pounds Thirteen Shillings and Four pence <hi>per Annum;</hi> the firſt half yearly payment to become due and payable the Twenty Ninth Day of <hi>September,</hi> 1696. and the other the Twenty Fifth Day of <hi>March,</hi> 1697. and ſo ſuc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſively every half Year, until payment of the Principal, either out of the Surplus of ſuch Fund, or otherwiſe, by Act of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament. Which Tax to be Collected and paid into the Exche<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quer, and tranſmitted to the Treaſurer of the Mint-Office at the Exchequer, and by him paid to the ſeveral Proprietors, under the uſual Penalties; as Forfeiture of their Places, and Satisfaction to the perſon grieved, out of their Eſtates. And if in any one half Year it ſhould happen to fall ſhort, or be not ſufficient to pay and ſatisfie to the reſpective Proprietors the half Years Inte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſt that ſhall be then due for the ſaid Two Millions, or what part thereof ſhall not be then, or before repaid, the ſame to be made good out of any the King's or his Succeſſors Revenue, not appropriated otherwiſe by Act of Parliament; for doing of which, the Lord High Treaſurer, or Commiſſioners of the Treaſury for the time being, ſhall be obliged under the like penalties, to grant his, or their Warrants to the Auditor of the Exchequer for the time being. But if at the Expiration of any one half Year, there ſhall be Collected and paid into the Exchequer, and tranſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted to the Treaſurer of the ſaid Mint-Office at the Exche<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quer, by Vertue of the ſaid Tax, any more than will be ſuffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cient to make good and pay the half Years Intereſt that ſhall be then due for the ſaid Two Millions, or what part thereof ſhall not be then or before repaid, the ſame then to go and be apply<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed towards repayment of the remaining Principal, part of the ſaid Two Millions. And as a proper Tax for the ſaid Fund, it
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:171482:5"/>is preſumed, the Duty upon Salt (at leaſt with ſome ſmall Additions) may be ſufficient, the ſame expiring the Seven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth Day of <hi>May,</hi> 1697. till which time, the Seventy Six Thouſand Forty One Pounds, Thirteen Shillings and Four Pence, that ſhall be due for the firſt Years Intereſt, due the Twenty Fifth Day of <hi>March,</hi> 1697. may be paid and made good to the Proprietors out of the new coined Money pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duced from the ſaid Two Millions, and ſo much appropria<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted thereout; though a Duty of Twelve Pence <hi>per</hi> Quarter upon all Malt, would be a better Fund, and perhaps ſufficient enough for Four Millions more, if the Shillings and Sixpences are likewiſe called in.</p>
               <p>Secondly, That ſometime before the Twenty Fifth Day of <hi>March,</hi> 1696. an Office be erected at the Exchequer, and made perpetual by Act of Parliament, to be called, The Mint-Office at the Exchequer, whereby His Majeſty's, and his Succeſſors Patents, a ſufficient Number of Officers, of known Reputation, as Comptroller, Treaſurer, Accomptant, and their Clerks, ſhall be always appointed for Execution of this Act, whoſe Places and Sallaries (the better to ſecure their Fidelity) ſhall be made for Life, and not to be forfeited but by breach of this Act, or ſome other Act, where by the Laws of <hi>England</hi> their Eſtates may become forfeited.</p>
               <p>Thirdly, That before the ſaid Twenty Fifth Day of <hi>March,</hi> 1696. the ſaid Officers ſhall prepare, and get ready to deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver out, Two Hundred Thouſand Notes or Bills, bearing each Ten Pounds <hi>Sterling,</hi> and payable with Intereſt from the ſaid Twenty Fifth Day of <hi>March,</hi> 1696. to the Poſſeſſor, after the Rate of One Farthing a Day, to be paid half year<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly for ever, or till repayment of each the ſaid Ten Pounds: Which Notes or Bills may be in the following or the like form. <hi>In Conſideration of Ten Pounds delivered in to one of His Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſty's Commiſſioners, for taking in Two Millions of Unmill'd Coin of the Kingdom, to be new Coined, according to Act of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment made in the Seventh Year of the Reign of King</hi> William <hi>the Third.</hi> This Bill entitles the Poſſeſſor thereof to the ſaid Sum of Ten Pounds to be paid him at the Mint-Office at the Exchequer, out of the Fund ſettled for that Uſe by Vertue of the ſaid Act; and for want of ſuch Payment, or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe by Act of Parliament, to an Intereſt of One Farthing
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:171482:6"/>a Day for Ever, out of the ſaid Fund; to be paid half yearly from the Date hereof: And at the Expiration of each and every of ſuch half years, to a new Bill of the like Tenor with this, which is then to be delivered up: And farther, until ſuch repayment of the ſaid Ten Pounds, this Bill, and the ſucceeding, to paſs currantly in all manner of Payments for Twelve Months from the date thereof, for Ten Pounds, and the Intereſt due thereon.</p>
               <p>Fourthly, That after the ſaid Twenty Fifth Day of <hi>March,</hi> 1696. the ſaid Officers ſhall Attend at the ſaid Office, from Eight of the Clock in the Morning to One Afternoon, every Day in the Week (except Holy-days) to deliver out the ſaid Notes or Bills; which they ſhall do to any Perſon bringing a Receipt or Certificate from any one of the ſaid Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners, that he hath paid him in Ten Pounds, or ſeveral Ten Pounds, which Receipt or Certificate they ſhall enter in a Book and File up, thereby to charge the ſaid Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioner; the Perſon bringing it, firſt paying into the Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſurer of the ſaid Office, ſo much as ſhall be due on each of the ſaid Notes or Bills for Intereſt; and ſuch Intereſt to be applyed towards repayment of the Principal Sum of Two Millions.</p>
               <p>Fifthly, That the ſaid Officers, after the ſaid Twenty Fifth Day of <hi>March,</hi> 1696. and before the Twenty Ninth day of <hi>September,</hi> 1696. ſhall prepare and make ready the like Number of Two Hundred Thouſand new Notes or Bills, bearing Date the ſaid Twenty Ninth Day of <hi>September,</hi> 1696. of the like Tenor with the Old ones, to exchange for them: And ſo ſucceſſively each half Year following for ever; aba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting in each half Year ſo many Notes or Bills, as the Surplus of the ſaid Fund ſhall have brought in, more than ſufficient to pay the ſaid half Years Intereſt, at the Rate aforeſaid, of the ſaid Two Millions, or what part thereof ſhall be then unpaid; firſt deducting out of ſuch Surplus, all Officers Sal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>laries, and other Charges; in Order to which, the ſaid Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers ſhall againſt and before the Expiration of every ſuch half Year make up an Exact Accompt in Writing of the produce of ſuch Fund, and the ſame Regiſter in a Book, for that purpoſe to be kept in the ſaid Office; and then before the Twenty Fifth Day of <hi>March,</hi> and Twenty Ninth Day of
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:171482:6"/>
                  <hi>September</hi> in every ſuch half Year, give Publick Notice in the Gazette (or ſome other ways in Print) for Calling in the Old Bills, and how many of them will be paid off in Money, and the Number of New ones to be given out, for performance of which they ſhall Attend as aforeſaid.</p>
               <p>Sixthly, To prevent Counterfeiting the ſaid Notes or Bills, that beſides Exchanging them half Yearly, the ſame to be cut Indent-wiſe out of Paper made for that purpoſe, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in may be ſome particular mark in the making, which mark to be changed every ſuch half Year, the ſame to be Num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bred, One, Two, Three, and ſo forward; and the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terparts bound up in Books, and kept in the ſaid Office, to be compared at taking in; and further, every half Year, the Printed part of ſuch Bills to be of a different Character from the preceding half Year, and each Bill to be Signed by at leaſt three of the ſaid Officers Hands, and ſtamp'd upon the Paper with ſome Seal, after the Method of Stampt pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per, which Seal to be likewiſe altered every ſuch half Year, and Notice given in the Gazette (or otherwiſe in Print) of the Form of ſuch Seal, and the perſons Names Signing the New Bills, and both the Seal and Printing Plate to be broke to pieces every half Year, as ſoon as the Number of Notes or Bills that are to be given out then are prepared.</p>
               <p>Seventhly, To make them every ways as effectual in pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments as the Silver Coin of the Kingdom, the Poſſeſſor only to have a Title to them, without any Endorſements or Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſignments thereon from the perſon giving them in payment, and all perſons obliged to take them in payment, as well in all publick Receipts of the King's Revenue, as in private Trade, or elſe be deprived the Liberty of proſecuting at Law their Debtors.</p>
               <p>Eighthly, That by the Twenty Fifth Day of <hi>March,</hi> 1696. at leaſt Twenty Goldſmiths, of known Reputation, be ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed as Commiſſioners for Executing the ſeveral before mentioned Articles, for taking in all Unmill'd Crowns and Half Crowns, and ſome Clipt Shillings, who (for Accom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modation and Diſpatch of all perſons) ſhall ſingly have power at their ſeveral Shops to take them in, and give Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceipts or Certificates to the Officers of the Mint-Office at the Exchequer, of all ſuch Sums as ſhall be paid them in, whereby
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:171482:7"/>they ſhall become chargeable therewith; which Goldſmiths ſhall be ſworn to do Juſtice without Favour or Affection, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the beſt of their Skill and Judgment betwixt the King and Subject.</p>
               <p>Ninthly, That the ſaid Twenty, or other number of Gold<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſmiths, to prevent any undue Practices to be committed by them in their being Covetous, one to take in more than the other, and being partial to particular People, ſhall be all li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted to equal Sums, as One hundred thouſand pounds apiece, and at their daily meetings to determine Diſputes of the good<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs of the Silver of the Crowns, Half crowns, and Shillings as aforeſaid, ſhall adjuſt amongſt themſelves once a Week, how much each Perſon hath taken in, and as nigh as poſſible the following Week ſo to order it, that each Goldſmith may be brought to an Equality therein with each other.</p>
               <p>Tenthly, If it ſhall be found impracticable by the Rules and Methods of the Mint, to take in from the reſpective Goldſmiths ſuch Crowns, Half-crowns, and Shillings, in one hundred pound parcels unmelted into Ingots, as aforeſaid, the ſaid Goldſmiths to have power to melt them down, always caſting two hundred and fifty pounds Tale, neither more nor leſs, into one Ingot; which they ſhall deliver into the Mint by Aſſay, where it being according to the Rules of the Mint reduced to pound weights ſtandard; the ſaid Goldſmiths ſhall pay into the Exchequer (when coined) ſo much as ſuch Ingot ſhall make Standard weight, to be accounted after the Rate of three pounds two ſhillings the pound weight, which they ſhall faithfully perform (upon Oath) without Fraud or Deceit, and as a ſort of a Check upon each Goldſmith by comparing the weight of their Ingots, and to charge them therewith in the Exchequer, the Comptroler of the Mint ſhall certifie into the Exchequer once a Week the groſs weight and weight Standard of ſuch reſpective Ingot.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="benefits">
               <pb n="9" facs="tcp:171482:7"/>
               <head>The Benefit of this Propoſal are many and great, amongſt which ſome are,</head>
               <p>Firſt, That hereby His Majeſty will be ſupplied with at leaſt Twelve hundred thouſand pounds of ready Money for this years Service of the War, and the Nation pay but a mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derate Intereſt for it, little more (or may be leſs) than ſix <hi>per Cent. per Annum,</hi> and yet by gradual and eaſie Payments repay the Principal.</p>
               <p>Secondly, This Propoſal chalks out a way for the like Supply (if there be occaſion) for Two years more, by next years taking in the Shillings, and the following year the Six<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pences unmill'd; whereby the whole Coin of the Kingdom in three years time (as little as can be taken for it) will be brought to its ancient Purity, and yet no ſingle Perſon be a Sufferer thereby, as by other Projects of leſſening the Coin they will.</p>
               <p>Thirdly, Allowing His Majeſty to grant leave to export Two hundred thouſand pounds of this new Money for his Service in <hi>Flanders</hi> (which is as much as was granted laſt Seſſions of Parliament to be Exported in Engliſh Bullion, and proved ſufficient, and it may be would none of it have been made uſe of, had not our immoderate Thirſt of Gold, and extravagant Riſe thereof, cauſed ſo great an Alteration of the Exchange for <hi>Holland, Flanders,</hi> and other parts of <hi>Europe</hi>) Yet the Nation will hereby be ſupplied this year with one Million of Caſh more than they have at preſent to carry on their Trade. For though it is true, that the two Millions that is called in, will be converted into Paper; yet it cannot be denied, but it will paſs better in Payments than the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Crowns and Half crowns unmill'd, which are now almoſt wholly decried, and become uſeleſs Caſh to any but Bankers, and Perſons well skill'd in them; and not amongſt them with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out great Quarrels and Diſputes. And ſince common Expe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rience ſhews us, That the Bank of <hi>England</hi>'s ſealed Bills (which are precarious) and bear but three pounds and ten pence <hi>per Cent. per Annum</hi>) are rather made choice of in Payments than Money; It may well be concluded theſe will be more accepta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble,
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:171482:8"/>that bear three pounds ſixteen ſhillings and a half-penny <hi>per Cent. per Annum;</hi> beſides having a poſitive Act of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment for the making them Currant in Payments. But more eſpecially will they be coveted and ſought after, if the Bank of <hi>England,</hi> and all other Societies of Men, or ſingle Perſons, be reſtrained by Act of Parliament, from giving any ſort of Intereſt for Money upon demand; the doing of which has been chiefly the occaſion of our preſent Scarcity of Silver Money, it being thereby monopolized, and thence naturally followed the Riſe of Guinea's to firſt twenty five Shillings, from whence by Art and Stock-jobbing, they are brought up to the now ſo great Price as thirty Shillings, that has brought in the preſent Inundation of Gold upon us; For it cannot be ima<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gined, that in a Twelve-month laſt paſt, the Plenty of Silver Money we had before, can be ſo far exhauſted the Kingdom, as at preſent it ſeems to be, that it ſhould occaſion Guinea's to riſe from two and twenty Shillings to thirty; but muſt be ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>knowledged the Effects of what was foretold at the erecting the Bank of <hi>England,</hi> that the Money of the Nation would thereby, and by their Example, by other Banks be monopo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lized: And unleſs ſuch Reſtraint be put to ſuch Banks, Society of Men, or ſingle Perſons, it will be in vain to new<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coin the unmill'd Crowns and Half-crowns, for the Subject will be ſoon deprived of the benefit thereof by their en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>groſſing it.</p>
               <p>Fourthly, This will be a great and good beginning towards the altering the Coin of the Nation, and reducing it to its ancient Purity, and thereby fixing a certain Standard or meaſure for our Commodities; and that by calling in the worſt, or at leaſt now moſt uſeleſs part thereof, and pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venting the great Vexation that is now amongſt Traders, diſputing what and what is not paſſable, and may be hoped to have that good effect to bring forth into Trade a great deal of Money, which now is hoarded up, for fear if it be parted with, the ſame Value may not again be obtained, but eſpecially will it have that effect to bring forth ſuch Money, if an Act of Parliament were paſſed, declaring that the Clipt Shillings and Sixpences ſhall likewiſe ſpeedily be called in, and made good in the ſame or ſome ſuch manner, to the Poſſeſſors of them, as the Crowns and Half-crowns are.
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:171482:8"/>And in truth, if only ſome ſuch Act were paſſed, inforcing for the preſent the clipt Crowns, Half-Crowns, Shillings and Sixpences, to paſs as the Coin of the Kingdom more currantly than they now do, it may be doubted whether that may not be better, than to meddle with the Money till the War is over: For if our Money be reduced to an Equality of Stan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dard, whether of the preſent Standard of Three pounds two ſhillings Tale for the pound weight of eleven Ounces two penny weight fine Silver; or as ſome unadviſedly project, to cut that pound weight into more Denominations; yet ſince, whilſt the War laſts, our Money muſt go away, it will, when ſo brought to an Equality, be more ready to convey away, than at preſent it is; for then it may very well be carried off in Lumps, whilſt now it is pickt up by piece-meal. And though it be true, that by new Coining our Money our pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Counterfeits will be wholly decried; yet ſince the true and proper Reaſon for calling it in, proceeds rather from the Want we now have of a certain and fix'd meaſure or Standard to Trade by (which ſuch an Act would greatly remedy) than from the Badneſs thereof; ſo ſuch Badneſs cannot be allowed asa ſufficient reaſon for calling of it in; ſince it may be feared three or four years may bring us under the ſame Misfortune again, and require a new Coinage: For ſince our Nation is ſtock'd with ſuch Perſons ſo well skill'd in that villanous Art, it muſt be expected our new mill'd Money (which is eaſier to be counterfeited than hammer'd Money) will be ſoon cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupted, and thereby (as ever was) the Ignorant impoſed upon. Neither can it be forgot, that when we had much mill'd Money ſtirring amongſt us, that a great deal of it was Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terfeited, and required the Care of Skilful Perſons to count it; for want of which care in the King's publick Receipts and Collections in the Country, and through a Cuſtomary Idle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs of taking and iſſuing Money by Content at the Exchequer, may rather be imputed the great increaſe of bad Money amongſt us, than from the Clipping of it; which ſince the Erection of the Banks, and occaſioning thereby the Money to be told over, and the good ingroſſed, has brought to light ſuch great Quantities thereof, that moſt People are ſcared into a Phantaſie that it is all Bad.</p>
               <pb n="12" facs="tcp:171482:9"/>
               <p>Fifthly, The ancient Standard of the Kingdom will hereby be preſerved, in which conſiſts ſo much our Honour, Faith, and Reputation; which is that a pound-weight Troy of Silver, containing eleven ounces two penny weight fine Silver, and eighteen penny weight of Copper, ſhould be cut into ſixty two Shillings; the leſſening of which, or cutting it into more Denominations, will be the greateſt Breach of the publick Faith we can commit, and is not leſs than becoming Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts in Compounding our Debts (which no Juſt Man ought to do, as long as he can give Security to pay the whole in time with Intereſt, as the Exchequer Mint-Bills now propoſed will) which Compounding will make us deſpicable to Forreign Nations, and leave us without Expectation of ever being truſted by them again, after ſo great a Violation of our Acts of Parliament, for it cannot be denied, that he that has Lent, whether Native or Forreigner, either the publick or to pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vate Perſons, a Pound-weight of Sterling Silver cut into ſixty two Shillings, and when he is to receive it back, is paid in Shillings, whereof ſeventy ſeven and a half are cut out of ſuch pound weight (the Rate projected by ſome People for our new Standard) is thereby cheated of one fifth part, or five and twenty <hi>per Cent.</hi> of his Money; and though it be true, that at preſent a Clipt Shilling will buy as much as a Shilling of full weight (the reaſon generally though erroneouſly offer'd for debaſing our Standard,) yet it is as true, that it would not ſo paſs, but upon Suppoſition that it will ſome time or other be made good by the Publick; and therefore is now become no more than a Pawn or Pledge of the Faith of the Nation; whileſt the Debaſing our Standard, by that Example, will be as the Difference of a Merchant, whoſe Creditors eſteem their Debts in his hands as good and valuable whilſt he remains in Credit, though in Eſtate he is worth nothing, and value them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves accordingly; and the ſaid Merchant's becoming a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt and compounding his Debts. Though it muſt be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſed, that herein our Credit begins ſomewhat to fail us, eſpecially with Forreigners, as by ſad Experience we find by the Exchanges altering to our Detriment from all parts of <hi>Europe;</hi> and that from want of ſome ſuch Act mentioned be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, and from the many Projects and Diſcourſes of Debaſing our Standard, which is already become a Demonſtrative and
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:171482:9"/>Concluſive Argument, that when ſuch Diſcourſes are put into Action by debaſing our Standard, it will not have the Effect propoſed, which is, That it will keep the Money in the Nation; it being true, That as the Exchanges fall, our Money will be conveyed away, and therefore will no more do it, than if kept up to the old Standard: And it's alſo plain, That if by Importation of Uſeleſs and Extravagant things to ſupply our Vanity and Luxury, and by the Neceſſities of the War, we become indebted to Forreign Nations, more than our own Manufacturies and produce of our Lands (abating our own neceſſary Conſumption) will make good, it muſt be ſatisfied them in Silver, which though we may cut it into what Deno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minations we pleaſe, will be ſtill valued by them according to the Weight, and the Courſe or Price of exchanging one Coin for the other alter accordingly; but more particularly as to us at home, ſuppoſing we have in the Nation one Million of Pounds weight Troy of Sterling Silver to be new coined, the cutting it into more or leſs of Crowns, Half-crowns, Shillings, and Sixpences, will not increaſe that Millions weight, or our Riches: And the cutting it into a lighter Coin than the an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cient Standard, will be a Cheat upon every body but Tenants, and immediate poſſeſſors of Goods; who indeed will be the only Gainers, ſuch poſſeſſors Goods riſing according to the debaſing the Coin, and the Tenant receiving in more Deno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minations the ſame weight of Silver, or part of that Million he had before, for the produce of his Lands, whilſt he pays his Landlord but the ſame Denominations of Pounds Sterling he formerly did, though of leſs weight, or leſs proportion of that Million weight; for it is certain that Coin is no more than a Meaſure or Weight of Silver eſtabliſhed by the Laws of a Nation, as a Rule amongſt themſelves whereby to rate their Commodities; and that the ſtamping it gives no value, but ſerves only as marks diſtinguiſhing that Weight: From whence it muſt follow, That as the immediate poſſeſſors of Goods, and all Tenants, will receive more of this Million weight of Silver in proportion than the Landlords, ſo conſequently the Land<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lord muſt be impoveriſhed, unleſs he can raiſe the Rents of his Land accordingly, which is well known to be almoſt im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſſible, Experience ſhewing, that though moſt Goods are riſen in proportion to the riſe of Guinea's, yet Rents either of
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:171482:10"/>Lands or Houſes are not. But plainer to evidence the Land<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lord's Loſs by this projected debaſing our Standard; Suppoſe, inſtead of One hundred pounds Sterling a Year, his Land were Leaſed out for One hundred Buſhels of Wheat of <hi>Win<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cheſter</hi> Meaſure, which is the Standard of <hi>England;</hi> after which an Act of Parliament is paſſed, That the <hi>Wincheſter</hi> Buſhel ſhall be leſs by one Fifth, or the old one raiſed to ten Gallons, eight of which ſhall be always eſteemed a <hi>Wincheſter</hi> Buſhel, and by One hundred of ſuch <hi>Wincheſter</hi> Buſhels the Tenants Rent duly paid, Will not the Landlord thereby have one fifth part leſs of Wheat of his Tenant than he uſed to have? And conſequently want a fifth part of Bread for Maintenance of his Family? And beſides for what other Neceſſaries he wants, as Wool of the ſame Farmer, to Cloath himſelf and Family with, muſt pay one fifth part of Wheat more than he uſed before, whereby he becomes a double Looſer; And by that means a Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man of One thouſand Pounds <hi>per Annum</hi> loſes four hundred Pounds <hi>per Annum,</hi> according to the preſent Standard of our Money, and the Rents of <hi>England,</hi> ſuppoſing them at Ten Millions yearly, will be reduced to ſix Millions, and the Land<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lords to live on no more Neceſſaries than will be purchaſed by ſix Millions of our preſent Money, whereby they will loſe four Millions yearly for ever, or eighty Millions of Pounds Sterling by way of Purchaſe, and the Tenants and Trades<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men Gainers thereof. From whence it is evident, how much it behoves all Landlords to oppoſe ſuch deſigned Alterations, but not only them, but all Perſons whoſe Eſtates are in Money will be equally cheated; but above all the King's Revenue diminiſhed, and indeed nothing but Confuſion be the Effects of ſuch Breach of Faith: All which will be preſerved by this Propoſal.</p>
               <p>Sixthly, This Propoſal can no ways have the ill Conſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quences that the calling in the Money, and obliging the Poſſeſſors to wait till the ſame is new coined will, for hereby he is immediately ſupplied with Money (or Credit as good as Money) to go to Market, and therefore will prevent that Stag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation, which for want of a due Circulation of the Money, might cauſe a Convulſion in the State.</p>
               <pb n="15" facs="tcp:171482:10"/>
               <p>Seventhly, and Laſtly, The Government will be hereby (as by all other Funds) the more eſtabliſhed, for almoſt every individual Subject will become Intereſted in the State by ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving ſome of theſe Bills in his poſſeſſion; and it's not to be doubted but that in this Selfiſh Age, Intereſt binds more than all the Sacred Bands of Oaths.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="objections">
               <head>The Objections at preſent occurring, are,</head>
               <p>Firſt, Theſe Notes or Bills are lyable to be Counterfeit, Burnt, or Loſt (as by Experience we have found all three hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pen to the Bank Bills) and not only ſo, but if the Poſſeſſor is only to have the Title to them, there can be no Relief againſt Robberies. To which it may be Anſwered, That by the Method propoſed, it will be almoſt impoſſible they ſhould be Counterfeited. But beſides, it may, and ought to be made Treaſon to do it; and if at laſt ſuch a thing ſhould happen, it is but the ſame Inconveniency that Money is attended with; though every half Year will diſcover ſuch Fraud, which is an Advantage we have not in Money. As to their being burnt or loſt, there is more to be ſaid to Obviate likewiſe that Inconveniency than there can be for Money, that having no Ear-mark; but theſe being Numbred, Publick Notice in the Gazette may chance to bring them to the Owners: Beſides, there may be a Clauſe in the Act, that if the Poſſeſſor gives Notice at the Mint-Office at the Exchequer, that he hath loſt ſuch a Numbred Bill, the Officers ſhall be obliged to en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter his Name, and the Number of the Bill ſo loſt, in their Books; and if it appears not within ſix Months after the time of its Currantry (that is, within Eighteen Months from the Date) the Perſon giving ſuch Notice, to have the Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, or a new Bill given him, upon giving an Obligation to the ſaid Officers to repay the Money if ever after the ſaid Bill ſhould be demanded of them. And the ſame Notice in the Gazette, and at the Mint-Office at the Exchequer, of ſuch Numbers as ſhall fortune to be ſtollen, may likewiſe chance to diſcover the Thief. But however, no Diſputes ought to be admitted of when they come to be paid or ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>changed at the ſaid Mint-Office, whether the Poſſeſſor came honeſtly by them or not, but always (after endeavouring by
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:171482:11"/>Examination to make what Diſcovery they can) readily paid or exchanged, that they may in every thing as near as poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible be like to Money: And therefore will behove all People to eſteem them as ſuch, and to take the ſame care of them.</p>
               <p>Secondly, Theſe Bills will be a force upon the Subject, and may have ſuch ill Effects, as to cauſe diſtinct Contracts in Trade before delivery of Goods, as whether to be paid in Silver or Paper Coin, and at laſt may thereby become uſeleſs to the Poſſeſſors. To which it's anſwered, That it muſt be owned a pleaſing force which brings Profit with it, as theſe Bills every day they are kept do, and prevents the many Diſputes we now have about the Silver Coin, which is of a fictitious value, and which in all payments is now a force upon the Receiver: And though it be true, the new Coin will not be a fictitious value, and therefore will be more in danger to be hoarded than the now Coin; yet common Experience hath ſhewn us, that at the Erecting the Bank of <hi>England,</hi> People parted with new and good Money for their Bills, payable with Intereſt of Two pence <hi>per Cent.</hi> a day, rather than their Money ſhould lye dead; and it cannot be doubted but theſe Bills will have the ſame Effect. And indeed this Propoſal cannot have its due and true Advantage, whilſt they, or any other Perſon gives Intereſt for Money on demand. Beſides when all the Coin is brought to an Equality (or promiſed ſo to be in a ſhort time, as before propoſed) people will freely part with that which lyes dead, for a quick and growing Stock of Caſh; and rather it may be feared, theſe Bills will be hoarded, and as the Bank Bills now do, cauſe Covetous people, and ſuch as are regardleſs of their Reputation, to make dilatory payments.</p>
               <p>Thirdly, This Method of making Paper paſs as Money will be a Reflection upon the Government, as though it was brought to Extremities, in not paying for every thing in Silver Coin. To which it's anſwered, that this is no more than has already been done ſince the War began by giving Tallies in payment. But if it be Objected, That as they were Sold ſometimes for great loſs, ſo theſe Bills may; Yet if it be conſidered, that the Government was then in its Infancy, and attended with ill Succeſs, the <hi>French</hi> being Maſters both of the Ocean and the Streights, which is now quite the contrary, and that ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nerally ſuch Tallies were ſecured out of Funds, that ſeemed
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:171482:11"/>doubtful, and not as this now propoſed made certain and perpetual, that Objection muſt vaniſh: And beſides, had thoſe Tallies been divided into as ſmall parcels, and made as eaſie, without Aſſignments, to paſs in Payments, as the Bills now propoſed; it is not to be doubted, but a great deal of Intereſt and Procuration Money might have been ſaved to the Nation, though it muſt be conſeſſed, ſuch methods ought not to be practiſed for too great Sums, or more than its be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieved the Silver Caſh of the Nation will give Life to; which common Experience ſhews us by the ſeveral Banks, may be double what the Caſh is. So that if the money called in, may produce Six Millions in Paper Credit, and that new coined, Three Millions of Silver Caſh, there will be ſuffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cient to Circulate ſuch Paper Credit. However the Calling in only firſt the Crowns and Half Crowns, may ſerve as an Experiment, before the Shillings and Sixpences be proceeded on. And if Two Millions of Paper money ariſing thereby, be found burthenſom, or not currantly to paſs amongſt the people, they may firſt be paid off by Parliament, though why they ſhould not paſs as well, or better, than the Twelve Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Thouſand Pounds of Sealed Bank Bills, it cannot well be conceived, (and yet they are generally ſwallowed up, and ſcarcely to be met with in payments) ſince the daily accruing Intereſt on theſe Bills is greater, and that Reward enough to give them a Currancy in payments; which had it been more, would have occaſioned their hoarding up too much, and not anſwering the Uſe deſigned by them, of facilitating and quick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning Trade; and therefore the making ſuch Paper to paſs in payments, as it is a Conveniency to Trade, can be no Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>flection on the Government, and the Mint-Office at the Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chequer will be no more than a Bank Eſtabliſhed by Act of Parliament, without the Inconveniencies attending a Bank, which amongſt many other things (as Experience hath ſhewn us) is the Monopolizing the Coin of the Kingdom.</p>
               <p>Fourthly, The Calling in the unmill'd Crowns and Half Crowns, and Coining them into Money after the rate of Five Shilling and Two pence the Ounce (which is the now Stan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dard) will occaſion it all to be Exported, now Silver bears ſo great a price. To which it's replyed, That the Coining them into Money as is projected by ſome, after the rate of
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:171482:12"/>Six Shillings and Five pence Half-penny the Ounce, will not at all hinder the ſame Exportation. For (as already has been proved) the Exchanges for all Parts will alter according to the debaſing our Standard; and whileſt we are indebted to Foreign Nations, our Money muſt go away to pay ſuch Deb<gap reason="illegible" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>d therefore (as is hinted before) it might be bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, during the War, not to meddle with the Coin, but only to paſs ſome Act, declaring the Clipt Money (as in truth it is, though diminiſhed) to be the Coin of the Nation, and that when called in, either at the Expiration of the War, or ſome other time, the ſame ſhall be made good by the Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick to the Standard of the Kingdom, which will keep the Money amongſt us, as wanting the true value, but yet as a Pawn of our publick Faith, will give ſome Life to it, and in great meaſure diſſipate thoſe fears the People now lye un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der of the Loſs falling upon the Poſſeſſors, whereby upon that our publick Faith, the Exchange to Foreign Parts may again riſe to our Advantage, and thereby, and keeping the Money amongſt us, help us to ſtruggle on longer with the War, than we can be ſuppoſed to do, if the Money be new Coined. But more eſpecially ſhall we be enabled, if ſome ſtop be put to the unreaſonable riſe of Gold, by limiting Guinea's not to exceed ſuch a price, which occaſions us to be more indebted to Foreigners, as it is a Commodity bought too dear, and too much of it, than otherwiſe we ſhould have been by the War. But ſince the general tendency of the people is for new Coining our Money, it muſt be ſtill affirmed, that the making our Standard lighter or heavier, will not hinder the Exportation: And that it will be found a miſtaken Notion, to think Silver will bear the ſame price it now does, when the money is new Coined. For if it be Coined at the rate of Five Shillings and Two pence the Ounce, Silver, that is, <hi>Engliſh</hi> Silver uncoined, will bear but that price, being prohibited to be Exported; neither would Foreign Silver, could we once be convinced, that neither <hi>Engliſh</hi> or Foreign Bullion ought to be Exported, but only our Money, which would ſoon make Bullion leſs valuable than our Money, and always keep our Mint (which now ſtands ſtill) at work, and our Money, as handſomer, and truer made, become more Famous through the World than
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:171482:12"/>Pieces of Eight, whileſt we have the Advantage of Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>facturing of it. And therefore it is propoſed, that for the future, all Bullion of Gold or Silver, whether in Pieces of Eight, or other Foreign Coins, or Bars, when once Impor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, ſhall be forfeited upon Exportation, and when brought to the Mint, pay as formerly for the Coinage; which will reduce Silver to Five Shillings the Ounce. And ſince ſuch Prohibition of Exportation may hinder the Importation, it ſhould be Lawful to Export the Coin of the Nation, paying Three Pounds <hi>per Cent.</hi> Cuſtoms, which ſhould be Collected upon any Sum amounting to, or exceeding Twenty Shillings, or elſe forfeited: Which Cuſtom being ſo ſmall, will eaſily be paid without fraud; and if all ſhould be Exported in Coin, that ſhould be Imported in Bullion, and Coined at the Mint, which it ſhould not exceed in any one Year, yet the Nation would be a Gainer about Six <hi>per Cent.</hi> by all ſuch Bullion, and beſides have the uſe of a great deal of Money, which now alwaps lyes dead in ſuch Bullion in Merchants hands, as Merchandize waiting for a Market: Whereas if they may Export the Coin at any time when ſuch Market preſents, it cannot be ſuppoſed they will loſe the uſe of any ſuch Bul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lion, but being coined, employ it in Trade. But it may be then ſaid, how, if all Pieces of Eight are coined, can the <hi>Turky</hi> and <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Companies be ſupplyed with them for their Trade? Which is eaſily anſwered, by their having (as above) Liberty to Export our Money: And it cannot be doubted but our Money will be ſoon in thoſe Parts in greater Eſtimation than Pieces of Eight, and beat them out of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pute, by which the Beneſit of Manufacturing the Money for theſe great Trades will accrue to us.</p>
               <p>Fifthly, and Laſtly, If all Corporations, Societies of Men, and Single Perſons, be prohibited from taking Money at In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tereſt, payable upon demand, and giving out their Bills ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cordingly, ſuch Prohibition muſt reach the Bank of <hi>England,</hi> and will be a great Detriment thereto, which ſince the Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribers to it were encouraged, and are Eſtabliſhed by Act of Parliament, would ſeem ſomewhat hard upon them. To which it can only be ſaid, that it ſeems doubtful whether ſuch Prohibition may not rather be their Advantage than
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:171482:13"/>Detriment: But ſhould it prove Prejudicial to them, it can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not be ſuppoſed, That Gentlemen of Honour, and of ſo much Affection to the Government as they are well known to be, can believe any thing bears hard upon them, that touches their private and particular Intereſts, when it evi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dently turns to the Benefit of His Majeſty's Government, and Common Good of their Fellow-Subjects.</p>
               <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
